Andreas Ellwanger, B.Sc.



• @ndrsllwngr, • @ndrsllwngr and in @ellwanger

+49 160 www.andreasellwanger.com

Andreas, a postgraduate student, currently pursues Computer Science at the Ludwig Maximilian University of Munich, Germany. He graduated in April 2018 at the LMU Munich with a Bachelor of Science in Media Informatics and Human-Computer Interaction. In the first half of 2019, he took part in the Erasmus+ program and studied CS abroad at the Leiden University, The Netherlands for one semester. At the moment Andreas works remotely for a Berlin-based startup called Aiderly GmbH as a Full Stack Developer / UX Researcher. Moreover, since last year, he is part of the Tech4Germany fellowship, Germany's first e-Government fellowship with Germany's Chief of Staff Prof. Helge Braun as a patron. Therefore Andreas had been staying in Berlin, Germany for three months to work as UX Researcher as well as Frontend Developer for the German government. Together with eight other fellows, they worked on topics related to digitalisation and e-government.

Interests: full stack react graphql rust

Work experience

12/2018 - present

Full Stack Developer / UX Researcher at Aiderly GmbH, Berlin, DE

react styled-components graqhql apollo hasura

- Devise UX standards and accessibility features
- Design and develop new features
- Maintain and adopt existing features of the Aiderly software

08/2018 - 10/2018 | Engineering Fellow at Tech4Germany, Berlin, DE

gulp html sass javascript vue figma ux

- Investigated user base, worked agile, iteratively prototyped, early user testing
- Redesigned web presence (approx. 85M Euro revenue in 2017) iteratively
- Coded accessible website, added mobile viewport, built design system

06/2015 - 08/2015 | Tutor in Computer Science at Ludwig Maximilian University of Munich, DE

Education

01/2019 - 07/2019

Leiden University, NL

Study abroad (Spring 2019), Computer Science, Erasmus+ Grant

04/2018 - present

Ludwig Maximilian University of Munich, DE

Pursued degree: M.Sc. in Computer Science

- Implemented P2P application based on Chord algorithm (developed by MIT) in Rust
- Built real-time interactive playlist web app with Scala is Frontend and Scala Backend

10/2013 - 04/2018

Ludwig Maximilian University of Munich, DE

B.Sc. in Media Informatics and Minor Human-Computer Interaction, April 2018 Advisor: Axel Hösl

- Thesis led to conference participation where peer-reviewed paper was presented
- Won 1st place at AI tournament with Settlers of Catan implementation in Java

05/2011 - 09/2013

Technical University of Munich & Ludwig Maximilian University of Munich, DE **Bioinformatics**

Scholarships and Grants

02/2019 Received grant from **Erasmus+ programme**, EU to study abroad at the Leiden University, NL for half a year (*Amount: 360,00 € (monthly)*, *Duration: 5 months*)

09/2018 Received scholarship from **VolkswagenStiftung**, DE to drive digitisation in Germany as a **Tech4Germany fellow** (*Amount:* 1.400,00 € (*monthly*), *Duration:* 2,5 *months*)

Volunteer experience

2013 - 2014 | Mentor at Lewis and Clark College, Munich, DE

Year of Study in Munich program

Certifications

24 June 2018 | Erasmus+ Online Linguistic Support (OLS), EU

English language assessment at level C2 CEFR

24 June 2016 | Leipzig University of Applied Sciences, DE

English in Computer Science and Information Technology at level C1.1 CEFR (Grade 1,0)

Research

Axis+Content [1] was written & submitted to DroNet@MobiSys 2018 by Andreas with the help of Axel Hösl and Andreas Butz. It received overall merit *accept* and *weak accept* by two knowledgeable reviewers, and was accepted as one of 6 full papers (out of 26 submissions). See also his publication profiles at ACM Digital Library, DBLP, Google Scholar and ORCID.

Talk

15 June 2018

Full paper presentation of Axis+Content [1]. At 4th ACM Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems,and Applications (DroNet 2018) @ MobiSys 2018. Munich, DE

At the conference, Andreas held an 18-minute talk to present the full paper and answer questions in the Q&A afterwards.

Skills

Languages | German (native), English (fluent)

Programming | Java, Scala, C#, Python, React, Rust, JavaScript, R, REST, SQL, HTML/CSS languages |

Other scientific tools | Git, LaTeX

References

[1] Andreas Ellwanger, Axel Hoesl, and Andreas Butz. "Axis- Plus Content-based Control for Camera Drones: Design and Evaluation of User Interface Concepts". In: *Proceedings of the 4th ACM Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications*. DroNet'18. Munich, Germany: ACM, 2018, pp. 9–14. ISBN: 978-1-4503-5839-2. DOI: 10.1145/3213526.3213529. URL: http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/3213526.3213529.